(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T21:28:35.019615",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
どうかしてる また同じシャツを
I must be out of my mind, wearing the same shirt again...
いないはずの人混みに探してた
Searching for you in a crowd where you shouldn't be.
誰といても 何を話しても
No matter who I'm with, no matter what we talk about,
映るすべて やだ また かさねている
Everything I see... oh no, I'm overlaying you again.
名前しか知らない なのにね こんなに
I only know your name, yet somehow...
気になるの……これって もしかして
I'm so drawn to you... Could this be...
ほら たった今 あたしのなかで 響くよ ハッピーミュージック
Look, right now, echoing inside me is a happy music!
運命の針を胸に落として 奏でる
Dropping the needle of fate onto my heart, making it play.
大事な日も まじめな時も 手加減無しの パワープレイ
On important days, when I'm being serious, it's all-out power play!
誰よりも先 あなたを見つけたくて
Wanting to find you before anyone else,
ダーリン 今度も あのシャツ着てきて
Darling, wear that shirt next time too!
こん火の！ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアでーす！
Kon-hino! I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Generation!
え、この度は『不知火フレア生誕祭2026』ビーマニ楽曲3Dライブ、始まりましたー！
Um, welcome to the Shiranui Flare Birthday Festival 2026 BEMANI Song 3D Live!
1曲目、え、ハッピーミュージック、ゲーム曲で今回お届けさせていただきましたが、どうでしたか？
The first song was "Happy Music," presented in a game style. How did you like it?
今回この衣装は、あの、ポエットちゃんに寄せてみてね、あの、ちょっと天使っぽい感じにさせていただきました。
For this outfit, I styled it after Poet-chan, giving it a bit of an angelic feel.
ハッピーミュージック大好きな楽曲なので今回歌わせていただきましたー！
It's one of my favorite songs, so I got to sing it today!
え、今回はですね、え、タイトルにもあるようにビーマニ楽曲ライブとなっております。全部ビーマニ楽曲で、構成させていただきました。
And this time, as the title suggests, it's a BEMANI song live, composed entirely of BEMANI songs.
コナミさんにね、あの、こんな熱い気持ちを、あの、一方的にちょっとお伝えさせて、あの、いただけたら、あの、全面的にですね、あの、ご協力して下さいまして
I shared my passionate feelings unilaterally with Konami, and they gave us their full cooperation,
なんとですね、こう見てください！てでーん！今回ステージすごいんですよ！
and look at this! Ta-da! The stage this time is amazing!
これですね、あの、コナミさんから素材を、あの、
They let us borrow assets from Konami,
お借りさせていただきま、全部あの、ご用意していただいたりとかしまして、めちゃめちゃ可愛い、あの、フレアがポッパーなので、あの、すごい大体ポップなんですけど、あの、
preparing all kinds of things for us. Flare is a Popper, so it's generally pop-themed, but
DDRとか、あの、下のこうキーボードはノスタルジアなのか、うーん、それともキーボードマニアなのか、どっちなんだいみたいなところですけども、こんな感じでね、こういろんな、こう、ここもねサウンドボルテックスみたいな感じで、すごい
like DDR or the keyboard below—is it Nostalgia? Or Keyboardmania? Which one is it? But like this, there are various things, like Sound Vortex here, it's amazing!
あの、BEMANI要素を詰め詰めにしたステージになりました。本当にありがとうございます！
It became a stage packed with BEMANI elements. Thank you so much!
ご協力いただきました。ありがとうございます！
Thank you for your cooperation!
ていうのはですね、これ完全にフレアの、あの、やりたい放題みたいなライブになっておりますの
This live show is basically Flare doing whatever she wants!
でですね、なんかすごい、この、これが結果的にとっても嬉しいお知らせに繋がるかもしれない、繋がらないかもしれない。それはちょっと、あの、今後の楽しみにと
And you know, this might—or might not—lead to some really happy news as a result. That's something to look forward to in the future,
いうことで、ハッシュタグは、え、不知火フレア生誕祭2026でございます。え、こちらでですね、あの、スクショとかポストとか、あの、色々
so the hashtag is #ShiranuiFlareBirthdayFestival2026. Please take screenshots and post about it,
してもらえると嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you do!
えー、この、あとどんな曲が出てくるのかは、あの、完全にフレアが、あの、好みとか、もう独断と偏見で選んでいるので、あの、皆さんさん楽しみでにしながら、え、待っててもらえたら嬉しいです。
Um, as for what songs will come out next, Flare chose them entirely based on her own tastes and biases, so I hope you'll look forward to them and wait excitedly!
あの、知らない方もね、「あ、こんな曲があるんだ！」と知ってもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。明日にはポップンしに行こうとかね、あの、サウンドボルテックスしに行こうとかっていう気持ちになってもらえたら嬉しいなって思うので、楽しみに待っていてください！
I'd be happy if even those who don't know them think, "Oh, there's a song like this!" I hope it makes you feel like "Let's go play Pop'n Music tomorrow" or "Let's go play Sound Vortex," so please look forward to it!
じゃあ最後まで見てくれないと、ちょっと泣いちゃうかも……シクシク、えーんえーん、ちらっ、えーんえーん、泣いちゃうかも！
If you don't watch until the very end, I might cry... boo-hoo, waah waah, peek, waah waah, I might cry!
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
Na-ka-na-i-de
本当の孤独も知らない
I don't even know true loneliness.
まだ淡い花びらに
Upon still-pale petals,
涙の粒 抱えたまま
holding droplets of tears...
ah さわらないで
Ah, don't touch me,
暖かなその手は
that warm hand of yours
あたしのすべて狂わす
drives everything of mine crazy.
ne 許さないで
Ne, don't forgive me,
傷口を押えて
pressing down on the wound,
微笑んでる あなたがいる
there you are, smiling.
もう 帰れないね
I can't go back anymore.
堕ちてく時の 甘い香り
The sweet scent of falling time,
繰り返すたびにひどくなる
becomes worse every time it repeats.
ダ・キ・シ・メ・テ
Da-ki-shi-me-te
いまだけ 好きだってフリして
Just for now, pretend you love me.
たった ひとつだけなら
If it's just one thing,
ぜんぶ ぜんぶ いらない
I don't need anything else at all.
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
Na-ka-na-i-de
本当の孤独も知らない
I don't even know true loneliness.
まだ淡い花びらに 涙の粒 抱えたまま
Holding droplets of tears upon still-pale petals...
ah 急がないで
Ah, don't rush,
真実なんか ほら どこにも落ちてないでしょ
look, the truth isn't lying around anywhere, is it?
ne 見つめないで
Ne, don't stare at me,
やさしいまなざしを
with that gentle gaze.
憎んでいる? 求めている? もう わからなくて
Are you resenting me? Seeking me? I don't understand anymore.
キスするときの あたしの顔
My face when we kiss...
キスするときのあたしの顔
The face I make when we kiss
もっときれいに見せたいだけ
I just want to look prettier.
抱きしめて
Hold me tight.
いつでも かわいいフリして
Always acting so cute,
真っ赤に色づく日を ずっと ずっと待ってる
I've been waiting and waiting for the day I blush bright red.
泣かないで
Don't cry.
本当の自分も知らずに
Without even knowing my true self,
まだ淡い花びらに 夢の重さ 抱えたまま
still holding the heavy weight of dreams on tender petals.
落ちてく時の 甘い香り
The sweet scent as I fall down,
繰り返すたびに ひどくなる
gets worse every time it repeats.
抱きしめて
Hold me tight.
いまだけ 好きだってフリして
Just for now, pretend you love me.
たったひとつだけなら 全部 全部いらない
If it's just that one thing, I don't need anything else.
本当の孤独を知らない
Not knowing true loneliness,
まだ淡い花びらに 涙の粒 抱えたまま
still holding tear-drops on tender petals.
あと もう 3センチ
Just 3 centimeters more
キミのくちびる まで
until your lips...
妄想生む イカした夢は なぜか
Why is this cool dream born from delusion?
これからってトコで いつも 途切れる
It always cuts off right when things are getting good.
わずかに 10センチ
Just 10 centimeters away,
伸ばす腕 ムナしく
reaching out my arm in vain.
シャット閉まる扉
Shut, the door closes—
ホームにひとり キミと ガラス越しに 目と目が合うあぁ
alone on the platform, our eyes meet through the glass. Ah...
ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
There's nothing to do here but laugh.
白線の後ろ 立ち上がんだ
Stand back behind the white line and rise up!
不覚にも涙が こぼれても
Even if unexpected tears spill,
ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
there's nothing to do here but laugh.
いつか キミまで 追いつくかな
Will I ever catch up to you?
帰って捨てちゃうほど
Enough to throw away when I get back—
代わりはいるぞなんて
saying "there are plenty of replacements"
ノウ、これどうなの？おじいちゃんおばあちゃん
No, what is this? Grandpa, grandma...
すぐに投げちゃ いけないんだよね
you shouldn't just throw them away, right?
今も昔も これからもずっと
Now, the past, and forever from now on—
代わりのボクは どこにもいない
there is no replacement for me anywhere.
ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
There's nothing to do here but laugh.
わかりあえる その日が来るまで
Until the day we can truly understand each other.
いつかキミまで追いつくかな
Will I ever catch up to you?
ふたりの距離は縮まるかな
Will the distance between us shrink?
ノドの乾きも忘れたまま
While forgetting even the thirst in my throat,
終わらないよ Chase!
It won't end, Chase!
キミの代わりはひとりもいない
There's no one else who can replace you.
キミの代わりじゃボクはいらない
But I don't want to be a replacement for you.
不覚にも涙がこぼれても
Even if tears unexpectedly spill,
もうここはひとつ笑うしかない
Here, I have no choice but to smile.
今も昔もこれからもずっと
Now, in the past, and forever from now on,
代わりのボクはどこにもいない
There's no replacement for me anywhere.
ああ、そうだったのかってきっときっと
Ah, so that was it, surely, surely...
わかり合えるその日が来るから
The day we can truly understand each other is coming, so
Chase! 今日もひとつ笑うしかない
Chase! Today too, I have no choice but to smile.
闇に放り込んだ
Thrown into the darkness,
想い届いていますか？
Are my feelings reaching you?
浅い夢の覚めに毎日
Every day at the edge of waking from a shallow dream,
伝う涙の理由はどこから
Where do these trailing tears come from?
きっと戻ってくると頬を撫でる手は冷たくて
The hand stroking my cheek, believing you'll surely return, is cold.
ぎゅっと広い背中を抱きしめた
I tightly hugged your broad back.
謳え謳え通い路恋歌 たとえ声はしなくとも
Sing, sing, a love song of the path we cross, even if no voice comes out.
届け届け通い路恋歌 愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
Reach, reach, a love song of the path we cross, for the person I love, I'll always be smiling.
淡い日々の思い出に毎日
Every day in memories of those faint days,
すがる二人の姿は儚げ
The sight of the two of us clinging is fleeting.
ぐっと押さえ続けた瞳の奥の優しさが
The kindness deep in my eyes that I kept holding back
ふっと帰り咲く刹那に溢れる心
Overflows in the moment it suddenly blooms again in my heart.
止まれ止まれ防人恋歌 たとえ声はしなくとも
Stop, stop, Sakimori love song, even if no voice comes out.
届け届け通い路恋歌 愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
Reach, reach, a love song of the path we cross, for the person I love, I'll always be smiling.
あなたの為君の為また出会う日までの約束
For your sake, for your sake, a promise until the day we meet again.
どんな想いが馳せようと笑顔で居よう
No matter what thoughts race through, let's stay smiling.
遠く遠く離れても
Even if we are separated far, far apart,
辛い時は歌に乗せて…
When times are tough, set it to a song...
ずっと待っているよとしかみつく手は震えてて
The hand clutching onto "I'll keep waiting for you" is trembling,
もっと強く深く深く抱きしめた
But I hugged you even tighter, deeper, deeper.
謳え謳え通い路恋歌 たとえ声が枯れても
Sing, sing, a love song of the path we cross, even if my voice grows hoarse.
笑え笑え通い路恋歌 暖かい陽はまだか
Smile, smile, a love song of the path we cross, is the warm sun still far?
ずっとずっと謳えるのは君の声がするから
The reason I can keep on singing is because I hear your voice.
届け届け防人恋歌 愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
Reach, reach, Sakimori love song, for the person I love, I'll always be smiling.
はーい！
Hi there!
皆さん、見てますか？
Everyone, are you watching?
はい、ということですね、
Right, so...
あきちゃんとはピンクローズを、リリカとは…
Aki-chan and I sang Pink Rose, and with Lilika...
すず、そして、え、さきむり連歌を、え、ソロで歌わせていただきましたー！
Suzu, and um, I got to sing Sakimuri Renka solo!
はーい。ま、ちょっとね、あの、どうしてこの曲を選んだかみたいなのはね、ま、ちょっとあの
Right. Um, as for why I chose this song, well, um...
その、なんかその、世代じゃないんですけど、なんかくの、好きな曲とか
It's not really my generation, but songs I liked,
なんか愛そうな曲、あとは、まみんながね、あの、馴染み親しんだポップンといえば、みたいな曲だったり
or songs I felt attached to, or songs everyone is familiar with like, when you think of Pop'n,
ま、でも、みんな好きな曲をちょっと選曲したら、やっぱバラなのでね、と
and well, but when I selected songs everyone likes, they're various, so...
とか、さきむり連歌は、もう、想い出があったらやばいけど
And Sakimuri Renka, if I had memories of it it would be crazy,
やばいんですけど、あの、好きな曲だったので、ちょっとチョイスさせていただきました。いや本当にかっこ難しかったです。
but it is, um, it was a song I liked, so I chose it. It was really difficult.
でもですね、え、今日はですね、あの、衣装は変わりましたけれど、
But today, um, although my outfit has changed,
今日はなんとですね、え、私のあの、希望で、え、今回ポップンミュージック、ハイチアーズ！遊べると
this time, um, at my request, I heard we could play Pop'n Music High Cheers! this time,
聞いてんですけど、え？どこで？どこにあるんでしょう？ちょっと探してみましょうか。
Huh? Where? Where is it? Let's go look for it.
どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ、これわああ！入ったこと！大好き！
Where, where, where, where, where... Oh! It's here! I love it!
え、すごいよ、この技術はすごい技術ですよ。
It's amazing, this technology is amazing.
みなさん、なかなか、あの、VTuber実機で遊んでいるところを見る機会がなかなかないと思うんですけど、
Everyone, you rarely get the chance to see a VTuber playing on actual hardware,
いや本当に、あの、コナミさん、運営さん本当にありがとうございます。今回はですね、こちらの可愛い筐体で遊ばせていただくんですけれど、
and truly, Konami-san, management-san, thank you so much. This time, I get to play on this cute cabinet,
あの皆さん、このステージ気づきましたか？こちらですね、なんとスピーカー、このスピーカーとかですね、
Did you guys notice this stage? This here, amazingly, speakers, these speakers and stuff,
あの、ステージ側にもあるんですけど、こちらね合わせていただいたりとかして、コナミさんがね、あの、ステージ素材をね、あの、ご用意してくださったんですよ。
are also on the stage side, and by matching them, Konami-san actually prepared these stage assets for us.
いや本当に本当にかがとうございます！なんかコナミさんにオンブにダッコで本当にすいません。
Thank you so much! I'm so sorry for relying entirely on Konami.
私今日やりたいことをたくさんね、あの、お願いして、あの、ダメ元でお願いしたらね、あの、たくさん答えてくださって本当にありがとうございます。
I asked for so many things I wanted to do today, and when I asked even though it was a long shot, you answered so many of them, thank you so much.
頭が上がりませんが、あの、せっかくなんできね、さっそくちょっと遊ばせていただこうかなと思います。
I can't thank you enough, but since we're here, I'd like to go ahead and play!
じゃあ、ちょっと、いいですか？とりあえずハッピーバースデーどこか叩かせていただいたね。ポンポンポンポンポンポンポンポンとこれ、この画面にね、あのクラッカーが
So, um, is that alright? First, let's play Happy Birthday somewhere. Pom pom pom pom pom... crackers appear on this screen...
映ったりとかするんですけど、今回は、えー、自分の、あの、マイカードで遊ばせて、いただけるということで、
and stuff, but this time, um, I'll be able to play using my own My Card,
あ、ちょっと暗証番号は魅せられないんでちょっと待ってくださいね。はい。
Ah, I can't show my PIN, so please wait a second. Yes.
そしてちょ、ちょ、ちょいのちょいと、入れさせていただきますよ。
And let me just enter it real quick.
遊ぶモードを選んで、ノーマルモード。わあ、ポップミュージックだ！いつも遊ばせていただいております。お世話になっております。ありがとうございます。
Choose play mode, Normal mode. Wow, Pop'n Music! I always get to play. Thank you for taking care of me. Thank you.
ということでですね、今日は、あの、ボーカルライブということで、ボーカル縛りでちょっと三曲をね、選ばせていただこうと思ったんですけど、
So today, um, since it's a vocal live, I thought I'd choose three songs with vocal restrictions,
今日のラインナップ、え、三曲は、ポップミュージックで、一番好きな曲音でまず遊ばせていただこうかと思いま、もう大好きなんですよね。
Today's lineup, the three songs, I thought I'd play my absolute favorite song in Pop'n Music first, I just love it.
で、まあ、あのちょっとハイパーで許していただきたいと思います。
And well, um, please forgive me for playing on Hyper.
今日選ぶ三曲の中で、個人的には一番難しい、難しいです。難しかったんですけど、一番大好きな曲なので、ちょっと選ばせていただきました。
Among the three songs I'm choosing today, personally it's the most difficult, it's difficult. It was hard, but it's my favorite song so I chose it.
ボーカルでこの曲選んでいいのかって話なんですけど、いやこの静かに始まる感じとね、
Is it okay to choose this song for vocals? Well, this feeling of starting quietly and...
あの、最後にくる、縦連とかが難しいんですよね。
And things like vertical notes coming at the end are difficult.
ライブはスウィート
"The live is sweet."
ほんとほんと
"Really, really!"
歌いたかったですね
"I really wanted to sing it."
もしもしもしまたなんか機会があったら歌わせてくださいてん
"If, if, if there's ever another chance, please let me sing it!"
どうしてもちょっと後半がグズグズになってしまう
"Somehow the second half always gets a bit sloppy..."
あー！神曲！ここがきつい
"Ahh! God-tier song! This part is tough!"
はあ、なんか取れたかな、大丈夫かな
"Phew, I wonder if I got it, is it okay?"
あー！一番！フレアが一番好きな曲です
"Ahh! Number one! This is Flare's favorite song!"
これで音符と読みます
"This is read as 'oto'."
あー大好き
"Ahh, I love it!"
あの推しです。推しのMZDDさんです、これどちらも
"That's my oshi. That's MZDD-san, both of them."
今日はですね、あの、選ぶ、あの、3曲のうちの2曲がちょっとMZDDの曲なんですけど、どうしてもみんなとやりたかったやつもあって、ちょっとそれを最後にしたいなと思ったんで、ちょっとMZDDで挟んじゃうんですけど
"Today, out of the three songs I chose, two are MZDD songs, but there was one I desperately wanted to do with everyone, and I wanted to put it at the very end, so I'm sandwiching it with MZDD..."
今回ダイアベでは歌わないのですが
"I won't be singing in DiVE this time, but..."
やはりね、あのポッピンといえばの中で、あの結構ナデシコロックじゃないかっていう方もねたくさんいらっしゃったので、ちょっとナデシコロックを戦わせていただこうかと思います
"As you know, when talking about Pop'n, many people said it's Nadeshiko Rock, so I thought I'd battle Nadeshiko Rock."
よろしくお願いします
"Please look forward to it!"
ちょっと速度の調整は大丈夫そうです
"Speed adjustment looks good."
これで行きます
"Here we go!"
凛として咲く花の如く
"Like a flower blooming with dignity,"
譜面もいいですからね
"The chart is also really good."
みんなの一番いい曲のひとつですね。一番いい曲なんて何個たっていいんですから。フレア今日何回、一番いい曲ののひとつって言ってるでしょう
"It's one of everyone's best songs. It doesn't matter how many best songs there are. I wonder how many times Flare has said 'one of the best songs' today."
口癖みたいに言ってると思います
"I probably say it like a catchphrase."
是非エルフレーにもたくさんしてもらいたいんですよね。タナミさんのボリ曲にはたくさんいい曲があるということを
"I really want Elfure to play it a lot too. The fact that Tananami-san's pop'n songs have so many good songs..."
ここがね、この後か
"Here, after this..."
こういうところ好きですよね
"You like places like this, right?"
咲いた
"Bloom!"
咲いた咲いたしののめ架け橋が避けない分かれていた
"Bloom, bloom, the bridge of dawn..."
いい曲であり譜面もいい
"It's a good song and the chart is also good."
ちょっとお馬さんパカパカみたいな感じで
"Kind of like horses trotting..."
ここ楽しいですよね
"This part is fun, isn't it?"
の、心
"...heart."
はいナデシコロック、ニューレコードだそうです。これ自分のカード、マイカードなので。はい、ニューレコードだそうです。やっぱ配信バフなんでしょうか。ありがとうございました。
"Yes, Nadeshiko Rock, it seems it's a new record. Because this is my own card, my own card. Yes, it seems it's a new record. Is it stream buff? Thank you very much."
いや、最後はですね、あの、みんなでどうしても叫びたかった、あの曲と言ったら、もう二択だと思うんですけど
"Well, for the very end, if we talk about the song we desperately wanted to shout along with everyone, I think there are only two choices, but..."
ちょっとどうしても、みんなと叫びたい
"I somehow really want to shout along with everyone..."
ハンザブに決まってるじゃないですか！
"It's obviously Hansabu!"
3、2、え？3、えっと、4、3、2、1で3倍アイスクリームなんで、みんなで叫びましょう
"3, 2, eh? 3, um, 4, 3, 2, 1 is 3-bai Ice Cream, so let's all shout it together!"
叫べるかな？ちょっと45だけど、これ45じゃないんじゃないかっていう、最後がすごい難しいですよね
"Can we shout it? It's level 45, but I wonder if it's not actually 45, the ending is super hard, right?"
これ、みんなで...
This was everyone's...
叫ぶのが夢だったんですよね。
dream, to shout it out.
ワールドラッシュとね、どっちやろうかなって
I was debating whether to do...
迷いましたらば、と、セカンドヘヴンにしました。
Gold Rush or Second Heaven.
なんか、ボーカルしばりと言いながら
I'm saying "vocal restriction"...
2曲英語っていう。
while playing two English songs. (Laughs)
カウントダウン、カウントダウンするよ。
Count down! Count down!
3倍アイスクリーム！
Triple ice cream!
みんなちゃんとした？
Did everyone do it properly? (Laughs)
もう回やりますからね！
We'll do it again, after all!
あの、正しい箇所はぜひ調べてください。
Please check which place is correct.
生きがいなんだ、3倍アイスクリームって言うことが生きがいなんだ。
Eating 3x ice cream...
生きがいなんだ。
is my reason for living!
みんな、この最終を見たあと明日はポップンやりに行きましょうね！
After watching this final stage,
明日ポップンやりに行きましょうね！
let's go play Pop'n tomorrow!
人の配信見てるとやりたくなりますからね。
Watching people stream Pop'n...
makes you want to play it too.
ちょっと恥ずかしいんです、手元見られてるの。
It's kind of embarrassing...
手元見られてるの。
to have my hands on display.
3倍アイスクリーム！
Triple ice cream!
急に叫ぶよ。
I'm shouting it suddenly! (Laughs)
ちょっとここ、むずい。
This part is tough.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
あ、みんなで3倍アイスクリームが言えて
Saying "3x ice cream" with everyone...
幸せだー！
makes me so happy!
いや、本当にありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you so much!
あ、待ってでも3曲終わっちゃった！
Wait, but the three songs are over!
あ、終わっちゃったよー！
Ah, they're already over!
あ、楽しかったー！
Ah, I had fun!
もう、なんか、今日はね、あの3曲しか遊べないので、
Today, since we can only play 3 songs,
ここで終わってしまうんですけど、あの、実機プレイはここで終わっちゃうんですけど、
it has to end right here.
いやだ、やばい、離れたくないかも。
I don't want it to end! I don't want to leave!
うわ、やだやだ。今日もうポップンするずっとポップンと離れたくないかないって。
I don't want this Pop'n stream to end!
うわ、ポップンしたいよー！
I want to play Pop'n more!
ま、ないものはないか。
Well, nothing can be done about it.
ちょっと切り替えていきますか。
Let's move on, shall we?
までですね、あのこの後も、あのみんなの好きな一番いい曲たくさん歌いますので、
Until then, I'm going to sing lots of everyone's favorite best songs,
ちょっと楽しみにこの後も観てもらえたら嬉しいなって思います。
so I'd be super happy if you'd watch the rest too!
じゃあみんな、次に行くぞ！なんだ次の曲は？
Alright everyone, let's go to the next one! What's the next song?
回転頭からない言語
Nonsense language from a rotating head,
ハイテンションと固いテンポ
high tension and a firm beat.
1先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法！
From a 5-match janken, I guide tactics for big opinions!
回転頭からない言語
Nonsense language from a rotating head,
ハイテンションと固いテンポ
high tension and a firm beat.
1先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法！
From a 5-match janken, I guide tactics for big opinions!
35÷2するはじけぬコンパ好き達に
35 plus 4 divided by 2, partygoers who don't burst open,
あっさり純情にねじ込むさばけた音楽鬼は
this sociable sound demon screwing into an obtuse angle.
どっからどこまでかわかんないハテナの音分けたんぱくけた
They dunno where from or where to, but anyway he divided the sound.
どいつとこいつのしゃらくりが垂らした汗拭きな
Everyone's winding chatter is a dangling handkerchief.
電ダン変化つけた電波に乗る大変馬鹿けた発言にゃぐうを作るや
An alteration in the radar and in the nonsense coming over the airwaves.
人格すら変わる程に上がる心拍数はたっぷりあこきだが、
If you start snoring, your heartbeat that's going up as much as your personality changes
にょい棒を握る天の力として生まれたときから続けてきたこの遊び方じゃうわっ
is really greedy, but there's power and land of the priest's staff and since I was born, I've kept on playing like this.
回転頭からない言語　ハイテンションと固いテンポ
Nonsense language from a rotating head, high tension and a firm beat.
1先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法！
From a 5-match janken, I guide tactics for big opinions!
回転頭からない言語　ハイテンションと固いテンポ
Nonsense language from a rotating head, high tension and a firm beat.
1先導するジャイケン5から大見解戦法！3通りから4通り！
From a 5-match janken, I guide tactics for big opinions!
本通りより本能に、任せた義理を梱包し、がっつり温厚に
From 3rd street to 4th street, from main street to the carnal desires,
本当にこのどこに跨がっていればdon't worry　ドンパチドンパチドン今日で、とことん交尾する日本島に
really, you don't have to worry if you extend over to this slow train. Don pach don pach don today, on this Japanese island where they're sexin' it up.
3通りから4通り！本通りより本能に、任せた義理を梱包し、がっつり温厚に
From 3rd street to 4th street, from main street to the carnal desires,
本当にこのどこに跨がっていればdon't worry　ドンパチドンパチドン今日で、とことん交尾する日本島にドンパチドンパチドン今日で、とことん交尾する日本島に
really, you don't have to worry if you extend over to this slow train. Don pach don pach don today, on this Japanese island where they're sexin' it up.
どんぱち どんぱち どん 今日で
Don pach, don pach, don, starting today,
とことん交わる 日本馬
mixing thoroughly, Japanese horse,
ぶち壊していくぜ 見本道理だば
smashing up the textbook examples!
O.K.O.M.E. RICE!
ライスでこめこめ RICE!
Rice for comin' comin' RICE!
O.K.O.M.E. RICE!
ライスでこめこめ RICE!
Rice for comin' comin' RICE!
スーパーパワー リラクゼーション
Super power, relaxation...
1合 150cc 正確無比に計ること
Measure 1 cup (150cc) with precision.
次に洗いだが直接お水をあせず二本指で
Next, wash without water directly, using two fingers
お水を計りJOIN！するのだ がその量米は1.2倍
JOIN the water! The amount is 1.2x the rice.
其の後は二時間ほどサディスティック（！）にお水に浸して
Then soak it in water for 2 hours sadistically (!)
ジャーの電源 ON！
And turn ON the rice cooker!
陽炎のような 底から
From the depths like a shimmering heat haze,
かき混ぜて
stir it all up!
おこめ おこめ おこめ ビタミン ミネラル 植物性
Okome, okome, okome, vitamins, minerals, plant-based!
おこめ おこめ おこめ おこめ ああ食べて ごちそうさごちそうさ
Okome, okome, okome, okome, ah, eat up, feast, feast!
おこめ おこめ おこめ おこめ おすもうさんの PowerをGET
Okome, okome, okome, okome, get the sumo wrestler's power!
おこめ おこめ おこめ おこめ ああ抱いてロマンティックに NIGHT FLIGHT
Okome, okome, okome, okome, oh hold me, romantic NIGHT FLIGHT!
おこめ おこめ おこめ 米屋のあの子をたぶらかそう！
Okome, okome, okome, seduce that rice shop girl!
食べ放題 食べ放題 ああ SO I LOVE YOU GET DAZE-！
All-you-can-eat, ah, SO I LOVE YOU GET DAZE!
おこめ おこめ おこめ SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER
Okome, okome, okome, SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER!
おこめ おこめ おこめ おこめ ああおこめ
Okome, okome, okome, okome, ah, okome...
おこめ おいしい
Okome is delicious.
真白と真夜中の間に立つ歌は
The song standing between pure white and midnight,
真っ白なケブトイ て耳元ではしゃぐ
pure white armor, frolicking right by your ear.
パーフェクト 僕らは完璧なんて軽い冗談だった
"Perfect, we're flawless," was just a light joke.
いつもの答えは 127の項目
The usual answer is item 127:
アスファルト蹴り上げたら トランクで決めて
Kick up the asphalt, pack it in a trunk,
急ぎ足で駆け出すのさ 今すぐバスで
and rush out right away on the next bus!
そしてホームシック抱えながら 人々は目指す
And while hugging homesickness, people aim
行き先はスマートに決めて 願いをかけたいのなら
for smartly decided destinations, if they want wishes granted.
真夏と真冬の間に生まれた歌は
The song born between midsummer and midwinter
まったりなカーブ描いて どこまでも進む
draws a leisurely curve and goes on forever.
パーフェクト 全ては同じ 似たもの同士だった いつもの答えは 同じ音なんだ
"Perfect, everything is the same," we were kindred spirits.
ソフトロックで暴れたら トークバックで
If we go wild with soft rock, via talkback,
yeah!
差し出しルール 12月のスポーツ
The submission rule: December's sports,
バジルパスタの試食
tasting basil pasta!
明日の噂話を トランクに詰めて
Pack tomorrow's gossip into a trunk,
逆回しでやり直すのさ 悪い性格
and redo it in reverse with your bad personality.
それでホームシック語りながら 人々は祈る
And while talking about homesickness, people pray,
行き先は道あふれてる 誰かが待ち受けるから
destinations overflowing with paths, because someone is waiting.
オレンジノイズ 浴びながら
Bathed in orange noise,
ショートカットで
with a short haircut.
yeah!
新しいブーム
A brand new boom,
聞き飽きたフレーズ
phrases I'm sick of hearing.
バブルアワーの法則
The law of the bubble hour!
さあ明日の噂話はトラックに載せて
Now, let's load tomorrow's gossip onto a track
風に乗せてバラまくのさ
and scatter it on the wind!
誰の計画？
Whose plan is this?
そしてホームシック笑いながら人々は迷う
And smiling through homesickness, people wander about.
行き先はそれぞれさ皆旅の途中なんだから
Destinations are all different, since we're mid-journey.
風に乗せて羽ばたくのは
Fluttering on the wind,
カラスの計画
that's the crow's plan.
行き先はスピードを上げてこの先も続くなら
If our destination picks up speed and continues on like this,
続くなら
if it continues...
はーいということで聞いていただきました曲は
Hi there! So, the song you just listened to was...
あのなんだめでいいですか ヒップロック お米タル ソフトロック
...what should I call it? Hip-rock, okometal, soft rock!
ということで ポルカと1曲 え、バカタリサーカスで2曲
So, we did one song with Polka, and two with Bakatari Circus!
え、なんかお米タルとかでもバカタリサーカスでどうしてもやりたかったんですよね
Um, even for okometal and stuff, I really wanted to do it with Bakatari Circus,
でもやっぱ歌のうまいメンバーなんでね、あのみんな集まって
and since they're members who are great at singing, we all got together
ソフトロックとかで暴れ散らしたりしたいなって思ったり、え、ポルカはね、やっぱりあのデスロウ好き
and wanted to go wild with soft rock, and since Polka loves Death Row,
ということでデスロウさんの曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思いました
I thought I'd love to sing a song by Death Row together,
のでこのメンバーで選曲させていただきました
so I selected the songs with this lineup!
ゲストはね、まだまだあのまだまだってあれですね、まだいるので
The guests... well, there are still more guests to come,
お楽しみにという事なんですけど、まちょっと早いんですけど、あの先にですね今回あのグッズの紹介を
so please look forward to it! But before that, I'd like to introduce some merchandise!
させていただけてもよろしいでしょうか？ また後でですね、あのグッズの紹介もまた改めて させていただきます、えー
May I go ahead and introduce them? I'll also introduce them again later properly.
ではですねいきます、え不知火フレア誕生日記念2026年
So here we go! Shiranui Flare Birthday Anniversary 2026!
え、さっそく、えーと1つずつ見ていきましょう！ まずは1つ目マフラータオル！
Let's take a look at them one by one! First up, the muffler towel!
イラストはハルマロさんに描いていただきました！ とってもかわいい！
The illustration was drawn by Harumaro-san! It's super cute!
持ち運びやすいサイズ感なので、ぜひたくさん使ってください！ 2つ目は こちら
It's a portable size, so please use it a lot! Second is this:
タンブラー！ イラストは形状さんに描いていただきました！
Tumbler! The illustration was drawn by Keijo-san!
今回なんとコナミさんに特別許可をいただいて推しの日に寄せさせていただきました！
We got special permission from Konami-san to align it with Oshi no Hi!
ありがとうございます！ 村雲MZDのおまじイラストなんですけど
Thank you so much! It's a tribute illustration of Murakumo MZD,
のんびり寝転ぶフレアの横にはアイビオのノアちょこちゃんとエルフれも一緒のとってもかわいいイラストとなってます！可愛すぎ！
where next to relaxing Flare are Noah-choko-chan and Elf-re! Too cute!
大容量で1Lくらい入って持ち手もついてて飲みやすいので
It holds about 1L, has a handle, and is easy to drink from,
ぜひみんなにも使ってほしいです！ 3つ目は こちら
so I definitely want everyone to use it! Third is this:
ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー！ おでかけ衣装のぬいぐるみがついたスマホショルダーです！
Smartphone shoulder bag with a plushie in her outing outfit!
ケースではないので様々な機種のスマホが入るんですけど、電気ショ対応ではないのでサイズが合わなかった人は
It's not a phone case, so if the size doesn't match for charging,
スマホ以外の小物を入れてください！ ぜひいろんなところに連れてってね！
please put other small items in it! Take it to lots of places!
4つ目は こちら キャップ！ イラストの私とおそろいのキャップです！
Fourth is this: Cap! It's a cap matching the one in the illustration!
今回のコンセプトで帽子はどうしても外せなかったので
For this concept, I just couldn't leave out a hat,
前に出したものとは色とデザインを変えてみました！ どうかな？ かわいいかな？ かっこいいかな？
so I changed the color and design! Cute? Cool?
シンプルめのデザインなので季節問わずかぶれるキャップです！
It's a simple design, so it's a cap you can wear any season!
みんなもおそろいにしてくれたら嬉しいな！ 5つ目は こちら
I'd be happy if everyone wore matching ones! Fifth is this:
シチュエーションボイス フレアと一緒に公園デート！
Situation Voice: A park date with Flare!
今回のグッズのイラストにあったような雰囲気のシチュエーションボイスがついてます！
It comes with a situation voice fitting the merchandise illustration!
みんなよかったら聞いてね！ 最後にフルセット！
Everyone, please listen! Finally, the Full Set!
数量限定ver.は直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード！ 通常版は箔押し複製メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
Limited version has a signed card, and regular has a replica card!
ふう！ 駆け足だったけど どれもすごく可愛くて使いやすいと思うので
Phew! They're all super cute and easy to use,
ぜひみんなゲットしてもらえると嬉しいです！
so I'd be so happy if you get them!
作ってるかな？
Are you making it?
みんなまだ帰らないでね
Everyone, don't go home yet,
この後も楽しんでね
enjoy the rest of the time too!
追いかけても 追いかけても
Even if I chase, even if I chase,
するり指を抜ける水のように
like water slipping through my fingers.
あなただけに あなただけに 見つめられたなら
If I were gazed at by you alone, by you alone,
星のない夜に 夢でもつかまえて
catch me even in a dream on a starless night.
流れる雲に思う
Thinking of passing clouds,
行き場のないこの心
this heart with nowhere to go.
いつか見た日の明日も
Even tomorrow, like a day I once saw,
青い通り雨
is a passing blue shower.
色づいた花びら 揺るぐ
The colored petals, wavering
ぬもりも 激しささえも
warmth, even the intensity,
切なさの裏側だけを残していくだけの刹那
leaving only the reverse side of sorrow—just a fleeting moment.
かなうのなら かなうのなら
If it could come true, if it could come true,
駆け出していきたい風の中
I want to run out into the wind.
あなただけを あなただけを
If I gazed at you alone, at you alone,
見つめたなら 羽ばたく蝶のように
like a fluttering butterfly,
夢なら見せないで
if it's a dream, don't show it to me.
星のない夜に 見出した
In a starless night, I found...
巡る季節を忘れて
forgetting the revolving seasons,
いつか来る朝を隠す涙色
the tears hiding the coming morning.
絡む指 しやめく息
Intertwining fingers, gasping breaths,
登りつめ落ちゆく心
a heart climbing up and falling down.
ひとときのぬくもりさえも
Without even forgetting that fleeting warmth,
忘れられずに また一人
I am alone once again.
追いかけたら 追いかけたら
If I chase, if I chase,
奪い消えてしまう月の影
the shadow of the moon will vanish.
あなただけに あなただけに
If I were touched by you alone, by you alone,
触れられたら 煌めく星のように
like a sparkling star,
嘘なら抱きしめて
if it's a lie, hold me tight.
届くのなら 届くのなら
If it could reach, if it could reach,
明日さえいらない戻らない
I don't even need tomorrow, it won't return.
離れてても 離れてても
Even if we are apart, even if we are apart,
心焦がす炎はあなただけ
the flame scorching my heart is only you.
追いかけても 追いかけても
Even if I chase, even if I chase,
するり指を抜ける水のように
like water slipping through my fingers,
私だけが 私だけが
I reach out my hand as if I alone
時を止めたように手を伸ばす
stopped time.
かなうのなら かなうのなら
If it could come true, if it could come true,
駆け出していきたい風の中
I want to run out into the wind.
あなただけに あなただけに
If I revolve my heart toward you alone,
こころめぐらす 遥か朧月
a distant hazy moon,
嘘なら抱きしめて
if it's a lie, hold me tight,
夢なら覚えないで
if it's a dream, don't wake me up.
世界が輝くその瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとだけでも触れたくって
I wanted to touch it even just a little,
幻をのぞいて
peering into an illusion,
空間が重なって 溶けあう
spaces overlapping and melting together.
太陽と月のように
Like the sun and moon,
巡り往く空の残像
the lingering image of the passing sky,
時間を超えてはつながる 響き合うの
crossing time and connecting, resonating together.
大胆不敵な空想の輪郭を追いかけて
Chasing the outline of a daring and fearless fantasy,
広がっては飲み込んでいく
it expands and swallows it up.
世界が輝くその瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとだけでも触れたくって
I wanted to touch it even just a little,
幻をのぞいて
peering into an illusion,
空間を飛び越した
jumping across space.
未来を追い越すその瞬間
The moment we outpace the future,
いつでもこんなものなのさ
it's always something like this—
幻をのぞいたボクらの世界が溶けあう
our world, having peered into the illusion, melts together.
始まりと終わりのように
As if it were the beginning and the end,
響き合う音の感情
The emotions of sounds resonating together.
記憶を辿れば繋がる
If I trace my memories, they connect—
物語のように響き合うの
Like a story, they resonate.
変幻自在に組まれた想像のパズルは
The ever-changing, crafted puzzle of imagination
狂おしいほど美しいのだろう
Must be so crazy yet beautiful.
世界を飛び立つその瞬間
The moment of taking flight into the world,
どうしても見せたくて ごらんよ
I wanted to show you no matter what, look!
見慣れない風景にそう今 駆け出した
Running out now into unfamiliar scenery.
不安だった昨日はちっぽけな何気ない今日なのさ
Yesterday's anxieties are just a trivial, ordinary today.
幻が歪んだボクらの世界が重なる
Our distorted world of illusions overlaps.
本当はずっと 世界はボクを待っていた
Actually, the world has always been waiting for me.
本当はずっと ボクもキミを待っていたんだ
Actually, I've always been waiting for you too.
重なり合った声が遠く響いて届く
Our overlapping voices echo far and reach out.
聞こえるでしょう 目を開けて
Can you hear it? Open your eyes,
物語が始まる時さ
It's time for the story to begin.
世界が輝くその瞬間ちょっとでも触れたくて
Wanting to touch even a little of that shining moment,
ごらんよ 幻をのぞいて 空間を飛び越した
Look! Peering into the illusion, leaping through space—
未来を追い越し その瞬間いつでもこんなものなのさ
Outpacing the future, that moment is always just like this.
幻を覗いたボクらの世界が溶け合う
Our world that peeked into the illusion melts together.
はい、ということで、聴いていただきました、 「おぼろ」と「Harmonia」、2曲どうでしたか？
So, how did you like the two songs we just performed, "Obolo" and "Harmonia"?
「おぼろ」は、私の親友アイリスと二人で、なんとダンスを踊らせていただきました！めっちゃ難しかったー！
For "Obolo," my close friend Irys and I actually danced together! It was super hard!
どちらもね、大好きな曲なので、今回歌えてすごく嬉しかったです。
Both are songs I love so much, so I'm really glad I got to sing them this time.
はい、ここまでもね、盛りだくさんだったんですけど、ちょっとまだね、すごく嬉しいことがありまして。
Up to this point has been packed with so much, but I still have some more wonderful news.
なんとですね、今回、あの、ちょっとビッグな方をですね、お呼びさせていただきまして、え、ビーマニシリーズで、あのちょっと作曲をしてくださっている方をね、ちょっとお呼びしたんですけど。
Amazingly, we've invited someone pretty big today—someone who has composed music for the BEMANI series!
誰かな、誰かなと、ちょっと待ってくださいね。誰かな？誰が？
Who could it be? Just wait a second. Who is it? Who could it be?
え！？だ、いいんですかね？これちょっとよ、いいですか？
Huh?! Is, is this okay? Can we really do this?
ええ、あの、私が一番好きな曲と言っていました、え、音を作って 澱(おり)ております。wacさんです！
Yes! The creator of the music for the song I've always called my favorite... it's wac-san!
くるり？ こんばんは、よろしくお願いします！
Kururi? Good evening, nice to meet you!
ああ、よろしくおの願いします！今日はありがとうございます！ ええ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, nice to meet you! Thank you so much for today! Yeah, thank you!
つ、遂にやったんですね、えっと。
We, we finally did it, um...
やります。なんか、舌も伸びませんでした。 舌はね、伸びるんですよ。
We did. Somehow, my tongue didn't even stretch. Well, tongues do stretch, you know.
にょおっと。あ、そう。結構長い。 ま、今日はね、これが精一杯なんですよ。
Like *boing*. Ah, I see. Pretty long. Well, this is all I can manage today.
今日はこれで許してほしいということなんですけど、あの、ちょっとじゃあ自己紹介をしていただけたら、よろしいでしょうか？
So please forgive me for just this much today, but could you please introduce yourself?
あ、執り行います。東京都高遠く。
Ah, let's proceed. From Tokyo, Takatoku—
あ、すごい、あ、言って、言ってんですか？ コナミアーケードゲームよりやってまいりました。新人バーチャルYouTuberのwacです。
Oh wow, you're really saying that? I've come from Konami arcade games, new Virtual YouTuber wac.
よろしくお願いします。困惑… 誰って感じなんですかね？誰だよ、もう、何って感じなんですかね？
Nice to meet you. Confusion... Who is this supposed to be? Who on earth is this, really?
最近あの、よくね、あのライブリーとかでもやらさせていただいているので、あの、結構うちのリスナーとかも知ってる、とか、あの、もともと音ゲーマーさんとかも結構知ってくださって、見てると思うんで、あのwacさんのこと知ってると思います。
Lately I've been doing things on Libly and all, so a lot of my listeners and rhythm gamers probably already know you and are watching, so I think they know who wac-san is.
あれ、これもwacさんんだ、みたいなの結構あったから、あと、あるんですよね。
Right, people often go, "Oh, this is also by wac-san?" and things like that.
一旦ちょっとあの、遊ばせていただいた、あの、新教体の話とか、あ、是非。
First, regarding the new cabinet we got to play, ah, please.
あの、12月18日とかでしたっけ？
Um, was it December 18th or so?
12月18日より順次稼働させていただいておりました。はい。
It has been rolling out sequentially since December 18th. Yes.
はい、ピカピカポップ君モデル、先ほど遊ばせていただいたんですけど、いや可愛いですね、見た目すごい。
Yes, we got to play the Pica-Pica Pop-kun model earlier, and it looks so cute!
ですよね。あの、あと、めっちゃ可愛いですもんね。
Right? And it's super cute, isn't it?
個人的に液晶がめちゃめちゃ明るくて、すごい見やすいです。でっかいですしもんね。
Personally, the LCD screen is super bright and very easy to see. And it's huge, too!
そうなんです、よ。大きければ大きいほどいいですからね。そうですね、大きければ大きいほどいいです。はい。
Exactly. The bigger, the better, right? That's right, the bigger the better. Yes.
あと、あの、キャラクターがね、あの昔のキャラクターとかもすごい綺麗に映ったりするの、はい。
And also, even older characters are displayed so clearly on it, yes.
そうですね、皆さん、もう本当ね、今回ピカピカぽぷくんモデルが完成するまでは、
That's right, everyone. Before this Pika Pika Pop-kun model was completed,
もうポップンスタッフの皆さんもそうですけども、
all the Pop'n staff members...
Doss-low先生や、DJ Shakaさんや、ポーンさんや、ネコマタマスターさんや、Takaさんや、佐々木さんや、劇団レコードさん、警視くん、谷中くん、もういっぱいいます。本当に作っていただいた方々もいらっしゃいますし、京都運んでくださった方もいらっしゃいますし、
Doss-low-sensei, DJ Shaka-san, Pawn-san, Nekomata Master-san, Taka-san, Sasaki-san, Gekidan Record-san, Keishi-kun, Taninaka-kun... There are so many. Many people helped make it, and some even carried it to Kyoto.
感謝の気持ちで私生きております。はい。この場に立てたのも皆さんののおかげでございます。
I live with a feeling of gratitude. Yes. Being able to stand here is thanks to all of you.
はい、ありがとうございます。いや、それは本当によりこちらがありがとうございますなんですけれども。
Yes, thank you. Well, actually, we're the ones who should be thanking you...
この辿り着けたのも、本当にいろんな方々のご尽力があってのことですので。
And reaching this point is truly thanks to everyone's hard work.
はい、という事なんですけれども、ポップンミュージックのなんか初出し情報とかありますか？
Yes, that being said, do you have any brand-new info about Pop'n Music?
それはちょっと。あ、言えない？
About that... Ah, can't you say?
いや、言います。
No, I'll tell.
初出し情報って何が良いですか？
What kind of new info would you like?
私、一個人としてはやっぱりMZDの話とか聞きたいんですけど。
Well, as an individual, I'd love to hear about MZD...
MZD？神ですね。一番、神だから神ですし、あの、結構やっぱワクさんって、MZDのなんか半分ぐらいだと思ってて、
MZD? The god. Being the ultimate god, and I think Wac-san is about half of MZD,
半分？あの、やっぱ半分はポーンさんなんですけど。
Half? Well, half is actually Pawn-san.
えっとね、厳密言うとMぐらいですね。Zがポーンさんで、Dがその他みたいないな、くらいの配分ですね。
Strictly speaking, it's about 'M'. 'Z' is Pawn-san, and 'D' is everyone else, something like that distribution.
なので、ちょっとMZDの話ちょっともし話せる範囲で聞けたら嬉しいなと、
So, I'd be happy to hear about MZD if you can talk about it within a certain range.
なるほど。MZDの何を知りたいんだい？
I see. What do you want to know about MZD?
あの、キャラ設定とか、あの、Amazon川流系青文字ですか？
Um, character settings or... Is it the Amazon river-flowing blue text?
なんでかしらんです。
Who knows why.
でもなんか昔になんかAmazonみたいな槍持ってましたよね？影がですね。あれがAmazonなのかも知れない。
But didn't he used to hold a spear like Amazon? The shadow did. Maybe that was Amazon.
違うのかもしれない。そこなんですね。
Or maybe not. That's the point.
うん、多分。今も青文字に住んでるんですかね？
Yeah, probably. Does he still live in blue text?
多分、住んでる。これ、なんか、あの、公式さんと話すあれなんですよ。
Probably lives there. This is, like, talking with the official staff.
あの、ポップンはね、本当、公式が知らないこといっぱいあるんですよ。あ、そうなんですね。
Pop'n has so many things the official side doesn't even know. Ah, is that so?
はい、あの、皆さんの、あの、いろんな思いで出来ているので、生声公式こそ知らないこともいっぱいあるんで、後から付いたりとかすることもあるのかな。曲とかって、あの、なんか作られ曲作ってから、あの、キャラクターとか決まるんですか？それともキャラクターに当てて曲作ったりするんですか？
Yes, since it's made from everyone's thoughts, there are many things even the official side doesn't know, and sometimes things get added later. As for songs, do you make the song first and then decide the character, or do you make the song fitting the character?
あ、なるほど。結構、あの、ケースバイケースっていうか、特にMZDとかは本当に、でもMZDって決まること多いですよね、やっぱり。割とバージョン最後の曲だったりすることが多いんで、MZDありきで曲作んなきゃいけないことは多いです。
Ah, I see. It's pretty much case-by-case. Especially with MZD, there are many things already decided. Since it's often the final song of a version, we often have to make songs with MZD in mind.
あー。はい、特にこのキャラ好きな人が、このキャラに曲作って欲しいって場合もあります。
Ah. Yes, especially when fans of this character want a song made for them.
あー、なるほどー！え、新しいね、あの、ハリアーズにもMZDが出てくると、あの、フレアは期待しているんですけど、出てくるといいなー。
Ah, I see! E, new, um, Flare is hoping MZD will appear in HaRiA's too, it would be great if he appeared.
あの、なんか、うさ猫の時みたいに、なんかストーリー結構しっかりみたいなのって、なんか今後もあったりとかするんですか？
Um, like in Usa-Neko, will there be stories with quite solid plots like that in the future?
はい、なんか、ストーリー、どうなんすかね。あの、ポップンをお好きな方って、そういうストーリー的な、なんだろう、このキャラこんなだったんだみたいなのがわかるのが嬉しいのか、めっっちゃ嬉しいです。
Yes, story, I wonder. For people who love Pop'n, are they happy to find out such story-like, you know, 'oh this character was like this' details? It makes me super happy.
あの、推しの情報を常に募集しているので、お願いします。
Since we're always collecting info on Oshi, please.
マジですか。頼みます、ちゃんさん。頼むぞ、おねがいし。
Seriously? Please, -san. Please, I beg you.
いいですね、欲深いないと大事ですよ、はい。
That's good, having greed is important, yes.
私、今日、実は誕生日なんですけど。え、マジすか？そうなんです。おめでとう、誕生日祝いタイムしようか。あ、歌ってくれるんですか？
Today is actually my birthday. Eh, seriously? That's right. Happy birthday, let's have a birthday celebration time. Ah, will you sing?
おめでとうお誕生日（歌声）これ今日実証されますかっていって。ありますか？（笑）あの、誕生日なんで、もしよろしければあの、サインとかいただき、サイン？嬉しいな。
Happy birthday to you... Is this proven today? Is there any? (Laughs) It's my birthday, so if you wouldn't mind, getting a signature... A signature? I'd be so happy.
あの、今日、あの、2枚ちょっとサイン、あの、カード用意したんで、好きなほう。好きなほう、あの、やっぱり音ゲーマーっていうカードなんですよ、100吉じゃないんです。全然、はい。紙、紙じゃなくて、ピアノーズメンパスをちょっと2枚用意しました。あの、普通のアウトドックスなやつと、あの、猫、仕事猫の、あの、カードちょっと用意したんで、あの猫なだけに。
Today, I prepared two cards for autographs. Whichever you like. Whichever, um, it's a card for rhythm gamers, not 100-kichi. Not at all, yes. Not paper, paper, but I prepared two Pianism and Pass cards. A regular orthodox one, and a cat, work cat card, so just because it's a cat.
なるほど、猫だけに。どちらでも、どちらにも、あの、サインしてもらえたら、あの、嬉しい。ここら辺にきっと、あの、あとで出していただくと思うので。
I see, because it's a cat. If you could sign either or both, I'd be so happy. I'm sure you'll display it around here later.
大丈夫です。書きます、書きます。わかりました。（笑）よろしくお願いします。ありがとうございます。（笑）全てを消したら消えるように書き尽くします。
It's fine. I'll write, I'll write. Understood. (Laughs) Please. Thank you. (Laughs) I will write until everything disappears.
欲張る。欲張る。なんかやっぱり、あの、私、あの、BEMANIの楽曲が大好きなので、あの、なんかもし、いつか、いつかでもいいんですけど、あの、本当あの、いつかカバーとか入ったら嬉しいなとかって、ちょっと、おや？おや？ちょっと欲張りすぎました。ごめんなさい。だから欲張りすぎました。ごめんなさい。
Greedy. Greedy. I really love BEMANI songs, so if someday, even someday is fine, I'd be so happy if a cover or something gets included, or... Oh? Oh? I got a bit too greedy. Sorry. That's why I got too greedy. Sorry.
いや、フレアさん、お待たせしました。案件です。ありがとうございます。
No, Flare-san, thank you for waiting. It's a project (anken). Thank you very much.
この配信をする時にあの、案件なんだなとか思ってる君たち本当にいなかったでしょ。
None of you really thought this stream was a sponsored project, did you?
ありませんでした。
We didn't have any.
なんですけど、あの、今回あの…
But you see, this time...
なんと！今WACCAさんがやってくださったとおりちょっと
And guess what! Just as WACCA has shown us,
知らぬイフレア、BEMANIにコラボ…
Shiranui Flare x BEMANI collaboration...
決定しました！ありがとうございます！
Has been decided! Thank you!
やっったー！
Yay!
やりましたね！ありがとうございます！めちゃめちゃ嬉しいです！
We did it! Thank you so much, I'm so happy!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
なんか、ええと、どこを触れていいのかなと。
So, um, where should we touch upon?
どのゲームとしましょうかっていう話ですね。
Like, which game should we collaborate with?
えっ、ぽぷーん？
Eh, Pop'n?
まあ、そうですね、ぽぷーん、さすがにこれでしなかったらわけがわからないんですけども。
Well, yeah, Pop'n music, I mean if we didn't do it with them it wouldn't make sense,
ここまでして、そうですよね、もちろんぽぷーんもですけど
but going this far, of course Pop'n as well,
さらに今回、はい、SOUND VOLTEXと、
and even more this time, SOUND VOLTEX -
やった！
Yay!
ダンスダンスレボリューションと、
and DANCE DANCE REVOLUTION,
三機種でのコラボをさせていただきたいと思っております。
a collaboration across three titles!
すごい！
Amazing!
これは、あの私の、直感が、もちろん、もちろん曲ですよ。
This is... of course, it's about songs.
新曲いきましょうよ。
Let's go with a new song!
新曲？
A new song?
新曲！実はね、ちょっとね、この人がいいんじゃないかなって思ってるんですよね、曲作ってもらうなら。
A new song! Actually, I think this person would be great if they were to write a song for us.
誰なんだろう。
Who could it be?
はい、さっきほど、はい、MとかZとかDとか、はい、
Yeah, earlier, yes, M, Z, D, and so on, yes,
言ってたんで、はい、今回はそのZにお願いしようかなと思ってます。
I was talking about, so this time I thought I'd ask Z.
Zって誰だっけ？えっと、Z、Z誰だっけ？
Who was Z again? Um, Z, who was Z again?
ポです、ね、ポ。ポ、ポです。ぽ、ぽ、ぽ。
It's Po, right? Po. Po, Po. Po, po, po.
ポンです、PONという、あの、なかなかいい曲を書く方がいるんですよ。
It's PON, PON is someone who writes really great songs, you know.
はい、ポップンミュージック、先ほど、そうですね、あの、フレアさんはMDTの曲が好きっていってたんですけど、まあ1/3ぐらい作って、最近、最近結構MDTの曲いっぱいつくってますし。
Yes, Pop'n Music - earlier, right, Flare-san said she likes MDT's songs, but about a third of them, and recently she's been making lots of MDT songs.
まあ、それ本に歌うし、あの、女性ボーカリストさんの曲もいっぱい書いてるような。
Well, she sings them herself, and she also writes many songs for female vocalists.
はい、PONさんが、あの、WACCAさんとPONさんが、あの、一番好きなんですよね。
Yes, PON-san, WACCA-san and PON-san, are my absolute favorites.
マジすか？ありがとうございます！
Really? Thank you so much!
なんか、ちょっと涙が出ちゃう。恥ずかしくなっちゃいます。じゃあ、書いて、書いてきてください。
Somehow, tears are coming out. I'm getting embarrassed. Well then, please write one for us.
はい、ありがとうございます。めちゃくちゃ嬉しい！待ってます。せっかくなんですけど、あの、
Yes, thank you so much! I'm so happy! We'll be waiting. Since we have this chance, um,
来て、WACCAさん来て、いただいたから、あの、なんかよかったら、あの、直近に、あの、収録される楽曲を、あの、WACCAさんと一緒に、なんか、歌いたいなと思うんですけど、歌います？
since WACCA-san came and visited us, um, if possible, um, I'd love to sing a song that's going to be recorded soon together with WACCA-san, you know. Will you sing it?
いいでしょう！せっかくなんです、あの二人だけでやりましょう。
Sounds good! Since we have the chance, let's do it just the two of us.
あの、ピアノと歌だけで。
Just with piano and vocals.
え？行くないですか？
Eh? Wouldn't that be great?
え？別になんか、嬉しい、緊張します。
Eh? Well, I'm happy, I'm nervous.
めちゃくちゃ緊張しますけど、自分も。
I'm super nervous myself, but
頑張ります！
I'll do my best!
We'll do our best!
頑張ります。実はね、練習してます。自分、このために。
We'll do our best. Actually, you know, we've been practicing. For this very purpose.
楽しみ。はい、聞いていただきたい、ぜひ。はい、では、えー、フレア、WACCAさんに送る、聞いてください。
I'm looking forward to it. Yes, we'd love for you to listen. So, um, please listen to this dedicated from Flare and WACCA.
僕の飛行機
"My Airplane"
どこまで飛べるかを
Just how far can I fly?
確かめに僕ら 旅に出る
Setting out on a journey to find out.
夢は尽きることを忘れて
Forgetting that dreams eventually end,
草原を駆け抜けて行ったけど
I ran across the grassy plains, but...
幼い憧れと
With my childish yearning,
ほどけた指切り 絆にする
The unraveled pinky promise becomes our bond.
逃げ出せないから ただ空を見てた
Since I couldn't run away, I just looked up at the sky,
かっこ悪いから 嘘をついた
And because it felt uncool, I told a lie.
白いノート 1枚破って
Tearing out a single page from a white notebook,
今日付とさよなら託した紙飛行機
A paper airplane entrusted with today's date and a farewell.
風に乗って舞い上がって 青く溶けた
Catching the wind, soaring high, melting into the blue.
旅立ちの歌を背に 白い軌道追いかけて
With the song of departure at my back, chasing the white trail,
ここで見てた 浅い夢も
Even the shallow dreams I watched from here...
翼にして いつか誰かに届いてくれる？
Will turn into wings—will they reach someone someday?
僕の飛行機
My airplane.
乗りこんだ汽車が
The train I boarded
見上げてた空へ
headed toward the sky I looked up at
続くなら
if it continues...
夢を見てた遠い日々に
In those distant days when I dreamed,
取り残されてる記憶は まだ あの空を覚えてるから
the memories left behind still remember that sky.
絡み合って もつれ合って やがて一人
Entangling, tangling, eventually alone...
さよならの歌 胸に約束を数えてるけど
Counting promises in my chest with a song of goodbye, but...
ここで見てた甘い夢も 翼にして きっとどこまでも追いつけると信じてる
I believe that even the sweet dreams I saw here can become wings to catch up anywhere.
風に乗って 舞い上がって 青く溶けた
Riding the wind, soaring up, melting into blue,
あの紙飛行機は 誰の手に届いたろうか
whose hands did that paper airplane reach?
夢が覚めて 僕が空に還る時も ずっと変わらずに 僕は君の中に生きている
Even when the dream wakes and I return to the sky, unchanged, I live on inside you.
あはは、アレンジすごい！ ありがとうございます！
Ahaha, amazing arrangement! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
めちゃめちゃ貴重な体験をさせていただいて。
I've been given such a precious experience.
こちらこそ！
Likewise!
ありがとうございます。わくさんでした。
Thank you. That was Wack-san.
素敵なコラボです。
It's a wonderful collaboration.
いやいやもう本当にこの度は素晴らしい機体をいただきまして、こちらこそありがとうございます。
No no, really, thank you so much for giving us such a wonderful aircraft this time.
はい、今後ともぜひポップミュージック、Bメンシリーズをよろしくお願いいたします。
Yes, please continue to support Pop'n Music, B-men series.
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat us well!
はあ〜！いやあ本当に嬉しいですね、大好きな僕の飛行機をわくさんとい一緒にお届けしました！
Haa~! Oh, I'm really happy, delivered my favorite "Boku no Hikouki" together with Wack-san!
アレンジバージョンどうでしたか？めちゃめちゃすごくあったですよね！
How was the arrangement version? It was so amazing!
わくさんからこうご提案いただきまして、今回アレンジバージョンで歌わせていただきました。めちゃめちゃ嬉しい！
Wack-san proposed it to us, and this time we got to sing it in an arrangement version. I'm so happy!
もうなんか、思い残すことがない、あ、まだ思い残すことはたくさんある！
Like, nothing left to regret... Ah, there's still a lot to regret!
ねえ、だってみんなコラボとかもありますからね！
You know, because there are collaborations too!
あ、でですね、あの、ここで新曲が、出ます！
And, um, a new song is coming out here!
えー「Silent Flame, Never Fade」という曲になります。
It's a song called "Silent Flame, Never Fade".
で、作詞作曲がですね、fripSideさんの八木沼悟志さんに作っていただきました！
And the lyrics and music were made by Satoshi Yaginuma from fripSide!
配信の後MVも出ますので、お楽しみに、ということなんですけども。
After the stream, the MV will also come out, so please look forward to it.
こちらデジタルリリースはこのあと12時からとなっております。
Digital release starts at 12:00 after this.
そしてですね、なんと、この新曲「Silent Flame, Never Fade」が、ポップミュージックダンスダンスレボリューションサウンドボルテックスの3機種に、なんと収録されます！すげー！
And amazingly, this new song "Silent Flame, Never Fade" will be included in 3 arcade games: Pop'n Music, DDR, Sound Voltex! Amazing!
なんか、感想って言いたいけど、まじか！しかちょっと出てこないんですけど。
Like, I want to say my impressions, but only "No way!" comes out.
はい、ありがとうございます。この他の詳細もですね、あの生誕グッズも含めて、ちょっと最後にあらためてお知らせしますので、お待ちください。
Yes, thank you. Other details, including birthday goods, I will announce again at the end, so please wait.
ではですね、早速今お知らせしました、新曲をですね、ま聴きたいと思いますので、お披露目しようかなと、思います！それでは聞いてください、「Silent Flame, Never Fade」！
So then, as I just announced, I'd like you to hear the new song, so I'll unveil it! Please listen, "Silent Flame, Never Fade"!
静かに揺れ続ける炎を 名もなき道で照らし出す
A flame burning quietly, lighting up a nameless path
なくしていた未来さえ いまあなたと新たな明日を刻んだ
Even the future I had lost, now with you, I've carved a new tomorrow
静かに揺れ続ける焔
Quietly, the flame continues to flicker,
名もなき道照らし出す
lighting up a nameless path.
失くしていた未来さえ
Even the future I had lost,
いまあなたと新たな明日を刻んだ
now with you, I have etched a new tomorrow.
いくつもの夜を超えて
Beyond many nights,
紡いできた自分らしさ
I have woven my own self.
選択したその全てが
All the choices I made,
私をまた突き動かす
they stir me again.
強がってた訳じゃなくて
It's not that I was acting strong,
止まることが怖かったよ
I was just afraid of stopping.
迷っていたあの時もきっと
Even those days I was lost,
今のチカラになってるよ
surely they have become my strength now.
一人きりだと思っても
Even if I think I'm all alone,
気付けばそこにある笑顔が
if I notice, there is a smile right there.
私といつも一緒に歩いてくれてた
It has always walked with me.
その意味、そのチカラ
I will never let go of that meaning,
絶対に離さない！
that power!
加速していくこの想いは
This feeling that continues to accelerate,
いま翼を纏い出す
now begins to don wings.
私が私でいれるそれだけで十分だから
Just being able to be myself is enough.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない
is not because I became strong.
私を呼ぶその声と
With the voice that calls me,
重なり合った信じる世界の明日を
I believe in the tomorrow of this world.
傷つくこと躊躇ってた
I was hesitating to get hurt,
立ち止まったこともあった
there were times I stood still.
そんな時にこの背中を押してくれた
At such times, the gaze that pushed my back
その眼差し
was there.
迷いながら選んだ道
The path I chose while lost—
間違いさえ真実だと
even my mistakes were the truth.
その焔は闇を照らして私に正しさをくれた
That flame illuminated the darkness.
張り裂けそうに痛んでも
Even if it feels like it's going to tear apart,
この胸に刻んだ勇気が
the courage engraved in this chest
私をいつも支えてくれていたから
has always supported me.
今ここに感じ合うあなたと私の夢
Now, here, we feel our dreams together,
燃え尽きることの無い夢は
the dream that never burns out.
この大空に羽ばたいて
Spread your wings in this great sky!
涙さえも輝かせ
Even tears will shine,
誰かの夜を照らしたい
I want to illuminate someone's night.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない
is not because I became strong.
静かな焔を抱いて
Embracing the quiet flame,
何度だって立ち上がれること知ったから
I learned I can stand up no matter when.
たとえ世界が色を失くし
Even if the world loses its color,
光が遠ざかっても
even if the light moves away,
この名に刻む焔はあなたと私を繋いで
the flame engraved in this name connects us.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない
is not because I became strong.
私を呼ぶその声と
With the voice that calls me,
重なり合った信じる世界の明日を
I believe in the tomorrow of this world.
この後詳細お知らせ！まだ帰らないでね！
More details coming up next! Don't go away yet!
新しい情報発表していくよ！
I'll be making a new announcement!
改めて今回コラボするゲームは、ポップンミュージック、DanceDanceRevolution、SOUND VOLTEXの3機種です！
The featured BEMANI games this time are Pop'n Music, DanceDanceRevolution, and SOUND VOLTEX!
この3機種に先ほど披露した「Silent Flame, Never Fade」が収録されます。
"Silent Flame, Never Fade," the original song I showcased earlier, will be included in these games.
ご覧の日付からプレイすることができますので、お楽しみに！
You'll be able to play it starting April 3rd at 10 AM, so look forward to it!
さらにさらに、不知火フレアが歌うBEMANIシリーズのカバー楽曲の収録も決定しました！
Furthermore, we've decided to include BEMANI series cover songs performed by Shiranui Flare!
収録楽曲、収録機種、収録日時についてはご覧の通りです。
Check the screen for details on the songs, playable versions, and release dates.
そして！
And...
まだまだ終わりません！BEMANIアーティストとのコラボ新曲の制作が決定しました！
There's still more! We've decided to collaborate on a brand-new song with a BEMANI artist!
速報はポップンミュージック公式Xで発信予定ですので、ぜひチェックしてみてください！
Breaking news will be posted on the Pop'n Music official X account, so be sure to check it out!
さあ、ここからは各機種ごとのコラボ内容をまとめてご紹介していきます。
Now, let's go over the collaboration details for each game.
ポップンミュージックでは、なんと不知火フレアがポップキャラとして登場しちゃいます！
In Pop'n Music, Shiranui Flare is making her debut as an in-game character!
詳細は追って公式Xにて発表予定なので、お見逃しなく！
Details will be announced later on the official X account, so don't miss it!
DanceDanceRevolutionでは、ゲーム画面の見た目を自分好みに変更できるプレミアムカスタマイザーとして、コラボアイテムが登場予定です。
In DanceDanceRevolution, collaboration items will be available as premium customizers.
SOUND VOLTEXでは、これまで登場してきたネメシスクルーに不知火フレアも参戦します。
In SOUND VOLTEX, Shiranui Flare will join the Nemesis Crew, who have appeared in past titles.
こちらも詳細は追って公式Xにて発表していくので、忘れずにチェックしてね！
Details for this will also be announced on the official X account, so be sure to check it out!
ということで、今回はフレアがずっと愛してやまないBEMANIシリーズのオリジナルソング縛りのライブがしたい、というね、あの完全にフレアのやりたい放題ライブの企画だったわけなんですが、そこからこんなにたくさんゲームに実装されてしまうなんて、いまだにちょっと現実味がありませんが、
So, this was originally planned as a variety live of BEMANI songs that Flare loves, but I can't believe it's actually happening in the games now—it still feels surreal!
長く愛しているBEMANIユーザーさんも、え、末永く今後ともBEMANIシリーズのことよろしくお願いします。
I truly appreciate the BEMANI users who have supported me for so long, and I hope you'll continue to support the BEMANI series!
あ、不知火フレアもよければよろしくお願いしますということで、あの音ゲーマー独自の誰目線ですが、え、すでに遊んでいるエルフレはもちろん、まだ始めてないエルフレもこれを機に遊んでもらえたら嬉しいです。
And of course, for those who already play Elfrein and those who haven't yet, I'd be so happy if you started playing through this!
そして新曲もね、このあとMVが公開されるのと、0時にはリリースもされるので、たくさん聴いて、見てくれると嬉しいです。
And the new song's music video will be released soon, with the release at midnight, so I hope you'll listen to it a lot!
あとグッズ。え、今回ですね、少し早めにお知らせさせていただいたので、さらっと振り返るね。
Also, the merch! Since we announced it a bit early, let's do a quick recap.
マフラータオル、タンブラー、ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー、キャップ、シチュエーションボイスフルセット。
Muffler towel, tumbler, plushie shoulder strap, cap, and situation voice full set!
どれも可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひお仕事だったり、お出かけとか、スポーツとか、ゲームセンターとか行ったりとか、え、何でも使ってみてください。
They're all super cute and easy to use, so definitely use them for work, going out, sports, or at the arcade!
グッズの販売はこのあと21時からなので、数量限定もたくさん用意しているので、逃さずにね！
Merch sales start at 9 PM today, and we have plenty of quantity-limited items, so don't miss out!
グッズの話なんかはまた改めてお話しさせてください。
I'll talk about the merch-free talk in more detail another time!
今回は思いもよらないことが本当にたくさん起きて、運営さんもコナミさんもエルフレのみんなも感謝の気持ちでいっぱいです。本当にありがとうございます。
Today, so many unexpected things happened, and I'm just so grateful to management, Konami, and all the Elfrein. Thank you so much!
さあ、明日はゲームセンターに、いっちゃん？いっちゃん？ね、一緒に行こ？
So, shall we go to the game center tomorrow? Shall we go together?